<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sabyasachi Bhattacharya</title>
    <link>https://njoysubho.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Sabyasachi Bhattacharya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 15:34:39 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://njoysubho.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Fargate Task Networking</title>
      <link>https://njoysubho.github.io/posts/aws-fargate-task-networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 15:34:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://njoysubho.github.io/posts/aws-fargate-task-networking/</guid>
      <description>In order to explore more about deploying on ECS using terraform and github action I created a small project but as I try to deploy it on AWS ECS I found some interesting issue.
 So I created a services in a subnet , the subnet has rule that route all internet traffic to an internet gateway. The service has a simple task. I created all the infrastructure using terraform and deployed using github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traceid Logging with Micronaut</title>
      <link>https://njoysubho.github.io/posts/traceid-micronaut-log/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 10:58:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://njoysubho.github.io/posts/traceid-micronaut-log/</guid>
      <description>Distributed tracing is must have when we create our microservices . Frameworks like Spring Boot,Micronaut comes with the support of creating TraceId,SpanId and propagate to visualization tools like Zipkin,Jaegar . This post shortly describe what we need to add in order to log the TraceId in application or access log . Logging traceId helps us in correlating the logs . For logging I have used Slf4j with logback . In micronaut support for generating TraceId comes quite easily just matter of adding proper dependencies which can be found here https://guides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Istio - Introduction</title>
      <link>https://njoysubho.github.io/posts/istio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 10:55:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://njoysubho.github.io/posts/istio/</guid>
      <description>Adoption of microservices architecture is on rising. Teams reap benefits of microservices which enables them to deliver faster, chose a language stack for their choice, quick feedback cycle, etc but, this freedom and pace comes at the cost of complexity to manage a new distributed system which must work in collaboration with each other to deliver the business functionalities. Reliability, fault tolerance, Tracing , Observability are some must-have aspect in a microservice architecture, add to it the functionality of canary deployment, traffic shifting and suddenly there is a whole layer of support system that is required for a service to deliver reliably.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Start Journey for a modern application development</title>
      <link>https://njoysubho.github.io/posts/modern-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 18:56:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://njoysubho.github.io/posts/modern-development/</guid>
      <description>The technology landscape for developers is changing rapidly. From monolith applications to microservices, from an application deployed on-premise datacenter to cloud platform, also applications deployed on virtualized machines to the containerized environment, the shift is huge. As a developer, it is important to keep up to date with this changing landscape both upgrading oneself as well as looking for a new job. As there are a plethora of technologies and there are always much hype and evangelism around a new technology it is always good to start with a much stable language, framework, and tool.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>